Srini B

UX & UI Designer

Synopsis

With 8 years' experience I bring to the table an array of expertise from domain knowledge like Banking, Retail, Pharma, Real Estate, e-Publishing, Telecom etc. to strong technical skills in the field of UX, UI, Responsive Web Development and Mobile UI Designing.

Experience

Freelance UX & UI Consultant | ZipErase | Present

- Interacted with project team from US & UK, gather business and project requirements.
- Research & analyzed the requirements and came up with IA, User Stories, Use Cases, etc.
- Created Wireframes, Visual Designs, Interaction Design, Style Guide and other UI assets.

UX & UI Consultant (Contractor) | NeuDesic Technologies | Hyd. | Nov 2019 – Feb 2020

- Interacted with stakeholders to understand the business and user requirements.
- Performed UX Audit on the legacy application (SilverSheet), document the usability issues and come up with workflow solutions.
- Developed design system, style guide, create asset and sketch libraries for the new version of the application.

Sr. Product Designer | West Agile Labs | Hyderabad, India | April 2018 – July 2019

- SPOC for all the UX & UI needs across the company helping project teams in UX/UI activities.
- Day-to-day interaction with the clients/stakeholders, sales teams to determine the future requirements and project timelines
- Create brand and styles guides for marketing and developers.
- Brainstorm, design, develop and maintain responsive web and mobile applications on need basis.
- Manage UI team for a seamless flow of UI delivery to the backend teams.

Sr. UX & UI Consultant | Xfinity Comcast | Pennsylvania, USA | July 2017 - March 2018

- Understand business, existing portal, and mental model of the users, interact with multidisciplinary teams for user enhancements and implementation of new features.
- Designed a new mobile customers flow from taking a new Xfinity plan to add plan to cart to final delivery.
- Created visual designs and developed UIs for the new mobile module and get them integrated with the help of back end team.
- Tested the website for usability, user experience and UI issues.

UX & UI Lead | Wipro Technologies | USA, UK, India | Feb 2010 – June 2017

- Responsible for developing and managing all aspects of design and creative output to projects that I'm assigned to.
- Directs, oversees and mentors a team of visual and UX designers.
- Develops, implements, and manages the company's design strategy.
- Leading and defining the visual design process throughout the product lifecycle, from initial explorations to final deliverables.
- Hands-on, translating conceptual ideas into compelling experiences and dynamic visual presentations and turning usability findings into design improvements.
- Ensures designs are completed on time and adhere to the established specifications and standards.
- Collaborates with the Leadership team to create functional strategies and specific objectives for the husiness
- Leading visual brand identity for the products that we develop.
- Provide quality control over design outputs and production.
- Write case studies and develop POCs using new technologies to find out the project and financial feasibility, efficiency and maintainability.



(+91) 8008-267-450



www.srinib.com



tosrisri@gmail.com

Education

B.Sc Computers
Andhra University | 1997 – 2000

Diploma in Web & Graphics APTECH | 2004

HCI Workshop & Training IIT Mumbai | 2007

Skills

Rapid Prototyping, Wireframing, UX Research Methods, IA, UI Design, Interaction Design, Responsive Web Development, Mobile UI, Web Accessibility, Implement Accessibility, Section 508 compliance, Agile Methodology, UCD, Design Thinking, UX & UI Testing, Design Libraries

Prototyping Tools

Sketch, Figma, Invision, Zeplin, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Adobe XD, Axure RP Pro, Omnigrafle, Balsamiq, Framer.js

Development

HTML5, CSS3, Flexbox, CSS Grids, SCSS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular CLI

Project/Lead Activities

Rally, Trello, JIRA, GitHub, Dev Tools

Social

<u>Linked</u>In

KEY PROJECTS DESCRIPTION & RESPONSIBLITIES TECHNOLGIES USED

Project Name:

ZipErase Web Application

Role:

UX & UI Architect, Designer

and Developer

Company: Freelance

Client:

ZipErase

Description:

Ziperase is a data erasure software that can be used over a LAN via PXE boot, or from a bootable USB stick. The project is aimed at developing a web application that maintains ZipErase clients and various licensing aspects of the software.

Responsibilities:

- · Gathered Requirements with by directly interacting with the project team who are from US & UK.
- Come up with BRD, User Stories, User Scenarios, Use Cases.
- Develop rapid prototyping (wireframes) using Balsamiq.
- Get feedback from project team with the help of Invision.
- Brainstorm and iterate over prototypes.
- Design User Interfaces based on the frozen wireframes.
- Develop work flows and user flows and create clickable prototypes.
- Develop HTML UIs using Boostrap and Angular.

Requirements gathering, Wireframes, Visual Designs, UI Development. Balsamiq, Invision, Figma, Photoshop, Bootstrap 4, Angular

Project Name:

Portal Direct v1.0

Role:

UX & UI Architect

Company:

Wipro Technologies

Client: Wells Fargo

Location

Columbia, MD, USA

Description:

PortalDirect is an internal facing responsive web application catered to a close-knit who includes Investors, Collateral Managers, Relationship Managers, Financial Managers, Analysts and Accountants who invest/manage and monitor the CDOs and CLOs. The aim of the portal is to streamline the process from setting up a deal to manage/monitor and provide reports specific to the user along with presenting a transparent work-flow from end-to-end.

Responsibilities:

- Gathered Requirements with BA team by directly interacting with the stakeholders, Product Owner and business teams.
- Analysed, brainstorming and understand the business needs with BA & PM teams and planed the UX/UI activities for project.
- · Created wireframes, work flows, personas, task flows, visual design, responsive UIs & Style guide
- Manage UI teams at onshore and offshore, frequent interactions with offshore team to resolve their queries relating to UIs.
- Helped UI team of designers in developing other similar UIs for the application.
- Optimized and enhanced the portal to WIA-ARIA compliance.

R&A, RG, IA, Brainstorming, Wireframes, Visual Designs, RWD, Balsamiq, Photoshop CS6, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 3, jQuery WCAG2.0, Developer Tools, Accessibility Testing

Project Name:

Automated Plasma Dispositioning System (APDS v2.0)

Role:

UX & UI Consultant

Company:

Wipro Technologies

Client:

Wells Fargo

Location Westlake Village, CA, USA Description:

APDS performs functions that directly impact the release of plasma units suitable for further manufacturing. The APDS supports business operations in receiving and tracking shipments of plasma from Baxter internal and external third party plasma collection facilities during interim storage at the Baxter warehouses. When the plasma is released from the plasma collection centres and data on the units is received in the system, APDS shall create an electronic record of the shipment and manage further status changes to the units. This includes lab testing and Lookback information that may impact final release of the units to the manufacturer. APDSv2.0 enhanced version of APDSv1.0 with automates all the above said process.

Responsibilities:

- Strategic Planning: Did the maturity assessment i.e. identify the capability & delivery timelines of the project to
 apply user centered design methods across all phases of the project.
- Analysis: Understand the business process from various teams at different levels and current work flow of the APDSv1.0 from gathering blood to plasma segregation to end user plasma products.
- Gathered and understand the new additional business requirements from the business and the ground team who
 are working in the facility with the help of usability tools/methods like card sorting, affinity diagramming,
 personas, user tasks, etc.
- Analysed, segregated the old and new requirements and created wireframes followed with work, task flows and presented to the business and facility team for further review and feedback.
- Designed 2 variants of visual mock-ups and pitched them and got instant approval.
- Create style guide, user documentation and other document work needed for FDA.
- Implemented SEO and AA web accessibility as per WCAG2.0 standards.
- Worked closely with development team both at onshore and offshore to ensure high quality output within project timeline and parameters. Helped the teams getting the UIs integrated without any UI issues.
- Optimized and enhancing the portal to web and handheld devices with WIA-ARIA compliance.
- Tested the application with JAWS for AA computability.
- Verification of Design and User Documents for FDA approvals (As APDSv2.0 is treated as a product rather than a service).

R&A, RG, IA, Brainstorming, Mental Models. Personas. Use Cases. User Stories, Task Flows, Wireframes. Visual Designs, RWD, JIRA, SVN, Balsamiq, Photoshop CS6, HTML5, CSS3, SEO. Bootstrap 3, ¡Query WCAG2.0. Developer Tools, Accessibility Testing, Performance Optimization, Documentation

Project Name:

Xfinity Mobile Web Portal

Sr. UX & UI Consultant

Company:

Comcast Communications

Location

West Chester, PA, USA

Description:

Xfinity Mobile is a new service that Comcast launched in 2017 with an intent to get into mobile communication service business into US which has already a customer base of over 1.5 million. The current project is customer facing web portal with all the functionalities that are aimed at both new and existing users who are already using Comcast's internet and other TV services.

Visual Designs, Sketch 52, Invision, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 3, Angular 4, Git, Rally

Responsibilities:

- Understand the business logic and existing portal for user enhancements and implementation of new features.
- · Designed a new mobile customers flow from taking a new xfinity plan to add plan to cart to final delivery.
- · Created visual designs and developed UIs for the new mobile module and get them integrated with the help of back end team.
- Tested the website for usability, user experience and UI issues.
- Implement WCAG2.0 for web accessibility.

Project Name:

Sr. UX & UI Designer

Company:

Wipro Technologies

Client:

Wal-Mart UK

Location

Leeds, West Yorkshire, UK

Description:

ASDA Groceries Retail Website Walmart is a retailing website that sells almost all the products both online and in stores. And in the current project the aim was to add new business requirements, update & enhance the existing functionalities like add to cart by drag and drop, showing dynamic ads like new products and related products to consider on the webpage, without effecting other modules and optimise the already existing website there by gradually revamping the entire child website but retaining the branding of the parent with enhanced user experience with strict web accessibility and as per W3C standards.

Axure, UCD, Dynamic HTML, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, CMS, Photoshop, Dreamweaver. Tortoise SVN, JIRA, Eclipse IDE, AB Testing, JAWS

Responsibilities:

- Discussions Product Owner and PM for UI requirements.
- Co-ordinate, update & support teams across locations US, UK and India for implementing UI features.
- Creating UI templates i.e. unique pages and workflows and share with offshore team.
- Designing and developing new User Interfaces on par with the other ASDA branding.
- Website testing, user testing the new modules and features.
- Bug fixing by resolving all the cross browser issues from IE6 to IE9, FF3.6+, Safari4+.
- Implementing web accessibility in all pages.
- Website performance and optimization.